<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bosnia on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bosnia on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 19:27:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Info</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 19:27:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/info/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarajevo</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/sarajevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 19:27:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/bosnia/sarajevo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“ J&#39;ai 10 jours, je me souviens... L&#39;explosion terrible qui déchire
le ciel de nuit et fait pleuvoir dans l&#39;hôpital n&#39;est ni un tir de mortier, ni
un tir d&#39;artillerie, ni une bombe... C&#39;est un coup de tonnerre de mon tout
premier orage. Une colère du ciel qui me rassure, autrement plus impressionant
que le feu des hommes... Car je suis un orphelin de dix jours heureux de sentir
la nature plus forte qu&#39;eux. [...] et qui aime le bruit du ciel en colère. ” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;credit&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt; Enki Bilal, le sommeil du monstre &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s with expectation and many questions that I undertook my trip to Sarajevo,
the capital of Bosnia.&lt;br /&gt;
Also with difficulties.&lt;br /&gt;
I wanted to take a train when someone from the hostel I was in told me that trains does no longer make the connection from Belgrade to Sarajevo. A Turkish passer-by wanted to go there, and he booked a shuttle for
the both of us.&lt;br /&gt;
At first it was planned for 1am, but then we were told 4am, so we expected to leave between 5am and 6am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That how we leaved around 7am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a 6 hours trip, Having hardly slept due to day light, loosing the sensation in my leg but not the pain in my neck, I got out the car in the middle of the old town of Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-set&#34;&gt;The set&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old town of Sarajevo is split in two parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The West part is a legacy of the Ottoman Empire, and thus you&amp;rsquo;ll find Mosque,
small coffee shop to have a Bosnian coffee or a hukka, Bazaar and small house
and street with Turkish influence.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/coffee.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;A Bosnian coffee when perspective got the hell out of here.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The east part comes from the time the Austria-Hungary power occupied the
country. Huge building with sophisticate architecture, large streets, and
churches.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/cityhall.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;The city hall, a mix of two culture...&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And when I say that the city is split, it&amp;rsquo;s because you literally jump from one atmosphere to the other in
one step. Look East, you&amp;rsquo;re in Istanbul. Turn around, you&amp;rsquo;re in Vienna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mosque, Orthodox church, Catholic church and Synagogue in a one kilometers
square. Surrounded by hills who offers Olympic winter&amp;rsquo;s game facilities.&lt;br /&gt;
Business tower, mall, square, tram, museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And bullets impact on many building.&lt;br /&gt;
Grenades explosion remains painted in red to remember that each one of
them has killed at least thirty people.&lt;br /&gt;
Destroyed building.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/grenade.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;...&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-actors&#34;&gt;The actors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Franz Ferdinand Carl Ludwig Joseph Maria, Archduke of Austria-Este.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josip Broz Tito, President of Yugoslavia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Army of Republika Srpska, the Bosnian Serb Army.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The people of Sarajevo , 50% of Bosniak, 31% of Serbs, 15% of Croats and 4% of other friendly human life forms.&lt;br /&gt;
51% Islam, 31% Orthodox, 15% Catholic, 0.3% Agnosticism, 0.8% Atheism and
1.8% other friendly believers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-plot&#34;&gt;The plot&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first act is easy, everyone knows about it.&lt;br /&gt;
Franz Ferdinand goes to Sarajevo, is killed by member of the Black Hand, and
the Austria-Hungary empire invade the Kingdom of Serbia, which leads to the
first World War. Symbolic, but still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second act introduces Tito, the head of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia.&lt;br /&gt;
While he leaded has a dictator, from 1953 to 1980, and seemed to have barely
heard of human rights, he was considered by the most as a benevolent dictator.
Aka someone that makes all the decisions, but tells you that its for your own
good - so far like every dictator, and actually cares for his people and act
for their own good. It&amp;rsquo;s quite relative of course.&lt;br /&gt;
But people at this time seemed to have a good life, at least a better one than
within the other communist countries, some Bosnian guys told me.&lt;br /&gt;
Until he died in 1980.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of the final act, without knowing what was at stake.&lt;br /&gt;
After Tito died, the Muslims and Croats of Bosnia and Herzegovina asked for their
independence after a referendum in which 99% of the voters agreed.&lt;br /&gt;
While the rest of the world thought that it was a good idea, The Bosnian Serbs
wanted to rally the territory of the former Yugoslavia under a unique name,
their own.&lt;br /&gt;
The story being complicated enough, let&amp;rsquo;s say it ended up with Sarajevo being
besieged by The Army of Republica Srpska.&lt;br /&gt;
Picture a city without power supply, tram, and few food and ammunition.&lt;br /&gt;
Tanks and snipers on each surrounding hills, randomly shooting at citizens.&lt;br /&gt;
During 5 years.&lt;br /&gt;
And for everybody to try to keep a normal citizen live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only path between the city and other areas which wasn&amp;rsquo;t under the Republica
Srpska influence was the airport, hold by the UN.&lt;br /&gt;
But there was no way to supply the city there, as people crossing the airport
would have been shot by the Serbs, or stopped and escorted back by the UN.&lt;br /&gt;
So, well, they just dig a 800 meters long tunnel under the airport.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/tunnel.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;A few meters of the tunnel is still accessible&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of museum and exhibition now who depict what happened during
the siege. The most impressive thing is that people of Sarajevo did their best
to keep smiling, sticking to their everyday life even if they had to run when
crossing the roads to dodge sniper bullets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how does the siege ended ? In 1994 the UN successfully requested several air strikes
from the NATO, the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, upon Republika Srpska.&lt;br /&gt;
The latter were forced to drive back, as the Bosnian and Croatian were able to
regain the city surrounding.&lt;br /&gt;
The siege was officially over on 29 February 1996.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too many days in Sarajevo to have a glimpse of how awful were
the Balkan&amp;rsquo;s wars. And this siege is just one example among other genocide and
mass killings of civilians who happened at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it took many years for the rest of the world to look at these people and
acknowledge that something wasn&amp;rsquo;t ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t took me too many seconds to think about Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>