<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambodia on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cambodia on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In and Out</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because you might find this story funny, here how I entered Cambodia, how I let
myself guided by the events and how I succeeded to leave the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we are, Ho Chi Minh. This day was my last in Vietnam, as my visa would expire the day after.
I had just leaved a group of fellow backpackers I spend time with from Phong Nah to Hoi
An. Alone again, I jumped in the bus who would take me to Phnom Penh, Cambodia.&lt;br /&gt;
I knew they would ask me to pay 35 bucks for my visa at the border, when it
should have been only 30. I had planned not to play the game of corruption, and
when the driver ask the bunch of foreigner from the bus the 35, here I stand,
claiming that I won&amp;rsquo;t let that happen. With the consent of the backpacker team,
30 it will be, even if we have to wait one hour at the border.&lt;br /&gt;
Meanwhile the bus broke down, forcing us to wait for another one in the middle
of the highway, but our determination was still intact. Until the driver hand
me this mad Vietnamese lady on the phone, who made clear that if we wanted to
pay 30 bucks, they will do whatever would be possible to make it painful.
Meaning paying night time fee at the border, waiting one hour, and using bikes to catch the bus,
who won&amp;rsquo;t be waiting for us but five miles from the border.&lt;br /&gt;
We had the choice of eventually paying the same price in both case, so it was
just a matter of loosing either time or self-esteem.&lt;br /&gt;
We crossed the border in ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Phnom Penh, I headed to my hostel, with Angèle, nerdy French
girl, with who I would&amp;rsquo;ve probably not talk to if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for all our bus troubles.&lt;br /&gt;
She didn&amp;rsquo;t knew where to sleep so I was happy to lead her to the hostel, as well
as making a new friend before even setting foot in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few days, still strained by the aborted revolution from the bus earlier, I was
willing to forget about making any plan for a while, letting Angèle and her
strong and effective leadership driving us around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad about letting other people do all the searching and
planning job though. This is more like letting randomness - in that case other
people decisions - choose my path.
Raven and Lief, met in Sihanoukville, would have used dices to make decisions
while traveling together. Should be fun to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, chilling by the swimming pool in Phnom Penh - 6$ Hostel have swimming pool
there, why not - Angèle start speaking about her American friend doing a
work-away in Kampot, south of Cambodia, and that we could met her as
there&amp;rsquo;s many thing to see there. Still not willing to make any big decision of my own for a while,
I accept to take the bus to this funny named city.&lt;br /&gt;
That&amp;rsquo;s actually a weird but enjoyable feeling, going to a place you never heard
about, in a country you know nothing about - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t open a book or read on the
web about Cambodia at that time. You should try it, let&amp;rsquo;s call it a blind
trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kampot here I am, with Angèle and another solo backpacker named Kareen, who
will unfortunately be forced to leave us after she got quite sick from the traitorous
sun of Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our stay in this small but charming city went on, between paddle boarding,
bikes trip to the mountain, local food and a couple beers. I liked the group I
was with, Angèle, Madison, Lauren and other passing-by faces.
We eventually left this place with Angèle for the beaches and island of
Sihanoukville. Maddie would join us a couple days after, and I was glad this
chain of events made me traveling with these two awesome human being.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/moutaintrip.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;This picture may contain: Three friends, nature.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sun, beaches. I was still letting myself driven by the waves of
surrounding friends. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got drunk with people worth to meet, resulting in
beer-pong games, dancing and midnight swimming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, hangover, we would take a early - too early - boat to Koh Rong Sanloem,
heavenly island where we would enjoy a night in a cozy bungalow by the sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angèle, Maddie and me were now ready to go north, and after a short stay at
Battambank, the city of the five million bats, with vivid memories of our trip
in the Battuktuk, we reached the city of Siem Reap, were we would stay a couple
of days, before everyone would make their own way in different country and the
crew would eventually split.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/howdidigetthere.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Wait, how did I get there?&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, why telling all this story, when I usually find that writing about my travel stories is boring ?
Well to make a statement I guess, that the saying &amp;ldquo;fortune favours the bold&amp;rdquo;
hadn&amp;rsquo;t apply to me so far.
I tried a different way of traveling which happened to be successful in many
ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That could be a attempt to answer to a question we, backpackers and vagabond, ask each other
every day: &amp;ldquo;So, what do you advice me to do in X country&amp;rdquo;. And the answer to be
extremely different each time you ask a new person. While one might have loved a
certain place, another would tell you there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to do there.&lt;br /&gt;
Which isn&amp;rsquo;t a surprise at all, you don&amp;rsquo;t have the same expectation, weather,
people to hang out with, so the place itself isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to make an objective
review.&lt;br /&gt;
Now, you&amp;rsquo;re like: &amp;ldquo;So, where the fuck am I going then? What will be the best
for me?&amp;ldquo;. And most of the time, you can&amp;rsquo;t tell. More reason to make random
choices then, no?&lt;br /&gt;
The cool thing, is that you will have no way to know if you made the right call
going to that island rather than this other one, because you didn&amp;rsquo;t go to the
latter.&lt;br /&gt;
Rather than hoping to be lucky on your trip, tell yourself you were so far. You
can&amp;rsquo;t prove or deny it, hence a win-win for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, and I&amp;rsquo;m not the first to say it, the things you remember, enjoy
afterward and tell to peoples are either trouble, bad things, being sick,
loosing stuff, walking under the sun for hours or to the other extreme
unexpected events which belong to you and you alone.&lt;br /&gt;
And you can&amp;rsquo;t plan this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, without planning, without expectations, driven by my feeling in the
instant, I met wonderful people, among them Maddie, a huge smilestone in this
trip in Khmer country, and someone I will hopefully meet again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is time to leave Cambodia, and reach Bangkok. To do so, let&amp;rsquo;s book a night
bus !&lt;br /&gt;
Alone again, after a few beers for courage and several pool games against
locals - I&amp;rsquo;m improving a lot since I&amp;rsquo;m in East Asia, I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for the bus pickup.
Who&amp;rsquo;s late, of course.&lt;br /&gt;
When it finally comes, I need to hurry, of course, and quickly hop in the bus.&lt;br /&gt;
Roughly half a hour after the bus left, comfortably lying in my bunk,
a guy came and ask me if I&amp;rsquo;m going to Bangkok, and positive is my answer. His
answer however, not so, for this bus is going back to Phnom Penh. Having
already visited this city, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really looking forward to go back there, I
had Thai projects in mind instead.&lt;br /&gt;
Surprisingly chill despite the late 2am-ish hour, I waited on the front of the bus for them to drop me and
caught another bus going back to Siem Reap, in which I chatted a bit with a
French-speaking Cambodian.&lt;br /&gt;
Back in Siem Reap, I waited again, occasionally exchanging a few words with other
travelers passing-by.&lt;br /&gt;
Eventually, here&amp;rsquo;s a bus to bangkok, I double-checked, I&amp;rsquo;ll make it this time.&lt;br /&gt;
After one of the longest border crossing I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced, I&amp;rsquo;m able to see the tall
buildings of Bangkok, at last. For a trip that should have taken height hours,
sixteen it took. But that was less boring than regular without-pitfall bus
trip.&lt;br /&gt;
Make mistakes while traveling, it adds up to the experience in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/mysnack.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;This guy just stole my snack...&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampuchea</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/kampuchea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/kampuchea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Tuktuk Sir ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s probably the first thing you will hear when you&amp;rsquo;ll make the first step
on the Kingdom of Cambodia. You&amp;rsquo;d better get use to it !&lt;br /&gt;
If you were used to crowded streets in Saigon or other major cities in Vietnam,
people honking all the time for no reason but entertainment, you&amp;rsquo;ll find Phnom Penh, the
capital of Cambodia, much more quiet. Streets are larger and fewer bikes and
cars use them, barely honking. It&amp;rsquo;s like they overestimated the number of citizens,
or probably anticipating the years to come. I did got the feeling that Cambodia
is a country which is rebuilding itself. From what, should you ask. Well here&amp;rsquo;s
another country among too many who endured dictatorship and mass murdering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name &lt;em&gt;Khmer Rouges&lt;/em&gt; means, for Khmer people, being forced to
leave the city, hard working, suffering, losing family or friend, being lost by
family or friend, being tortured, death.&lt;br /&gt;
Polpot and his &lt;em&gt;Khmer Rouges&lt;/em&gt; destroyed the country for love of communism
ideology, and fear of being spied and overthrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healing it&amp;rsquo;s wounds, the country is developing itself at high speed.&lt;br /&gt;
New buildings, office are under construction everywhere in the cities, and
resorts and casinos popping along the coast.&lt;br /&gt;
Tourism is growing, the country and its inhabitants adapting themselves to
the increasing number of tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to rightly compare different countries and speak about them
when you&amp;rsquo;ve only seen a glimpse of how their inhabitants struggle with live and how they feel.
You should therefor take my stories as a sketch of the reality there, twisted
by a foreigner&amp;rsquo;s look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Hello ! Hello, hello, hello !&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one of the numerous kids you&amp;rsquo;ll see waving at you, big smile on their face.&lt;br /&gt;
Bob, old stager when it comes to traveling, behind his huge beard, would tell you that fifty per cent
of the population is under 20 years old. Only 3 or 5 per cent above 60.&lt;br /&gt;
On one side, a lot of young adult, result of a baby boom post &lt;em&gt;Khmer Rouges&lt;/em&gt;.
Tuktuk drivers, restaurant owners, they all have a large family to feed, and
if they are glad not to have endured the horror of the past, they are still having a
grudge against the government, which remains the same since 1997. Through rigged
elections, these Cambodian rulers do not seem to met people expectation regarding
wages and living condition. Apparently thing could change next year, as the
election will be overseen by an NGO, according to this Tuktuk driver from
Bantambank, sharing his story, a tear in the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s come back to these kids now. Some will just want to play with you and
practice their English, meaning their family is doing well. Some, although
friendly, will try to get some money from you. And here you are, struggling to
find out if giving them something will help them attends school, or if their
parents will keep the earnings for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/school.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Education remains a priority in many places.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s with mixed feelings that you could spend hours playing with local
children on a beach in Sihanoukville, while dreaming up what this country could
be in 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this.&lt;br /&gt;
What will all these kids, better English speaker than their parents, wishing brighter
futures, at the border between two separate culture, do when they&amp;rsquo;ll become in
age to rule the country ?&lt;br /&gt;
Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be something to see all these smart-ass boys and girls, owning a
country which has still many thing to offer in terms of culture, history and nature
despite the scares of war, bombing and dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps will it just become an other copy of these new developed countries, an other
touristic attraction in this amusement park called earth.&lt;br /&gt;
Or perhaps when you&amp;rsquo;ll come back there in twenty years, these same kids will
welcome you to their family as a wanderer traveling in a country not entirely
shaped for your exotic entertainment. A country owned by it&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants,
who doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about the expectation of this rich strangers, willing to prove
to the world that his two weeks vacation in Cambodia were far better than the
one his coworker spent in a surrounding country.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/novolcano.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Nice one.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>