<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambodia on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cambodia on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampuchea</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/kampuchea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/cambodia/kampuchea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Tuk tuk Sir ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s probably the first thing you will hear when you&amp;rsquo;ll make the first step
on the Kingdom of Cambodia. You&amp;rsquo;d better get use to it !&lt;br /&gt;
If you were used to crowded streets in Saigon or other major cities in Vietnam,
people honking all the time for no real reason, you&amp;rsquo;ll find Phnom Penh, the
capital of Cambodia, much more quiet. Streets are larger and fewer bikes and
cars use them, barely honking. It&amp;rsquo;s like they overestimated the number of citizens,
or probably anticipating the years to come. I did got the feeling that Cambodia
is a country which is rebuilding itself. From what, should you ask. Well here&amp;rsquo;s
another country among too many who endured dictatorship and mass murdering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name &lt;em&gt;Khmer Rouges&lt;/em&gt; means, for Khmer people, being forced to
leave the city, hard working, suffering, losing family or friend, being lost by
family or friend, being tortured, death.&lt;br /&gt;
Polpot and his &lt;em&gt;Khmer Rouges&lt;/em&gt; destroyed the country for love of communism
ideology, and fear of being spy and stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healing it&amp;rsquo;s wounds, the country is developing itself at high speed.&lt;br /&gt;
New buildings, office are under construction everywhere in the cities, and
resorts and casinos popping along the coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>