<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovakia on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovakia on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 19:27:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Info</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 19:27:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/info/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchhiking 101</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/hitchhiking-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:24:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/slovakia/hitchhiking-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Any man who can hitch the length and breadth of the galaxy, rough it, slum it, struggle against terrible odds, win through, and still knows where his towel is is clearly a man to be reckoned with.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;credit&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt; Douglas Adams &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bratislava is one hour from Vienna, so it was the perfect time to try
hitchicking.&lt;br /&gt;
I thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always been afraid of getting stuck somewere in the
middle of a foreign country, and that&amp;rsquo;s why I only used buses so far, but now
is the time to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;v never done hitchhicking before, and didn&amp;rsquo;t knew were to start. Fortunatly,
we live in a great century and the World Wild Web has an answer for you.&lt;br /&gt;
A few researches, and I found the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hitchwiki.org/en/Main_Page&#34;&gt;golden mine&lt;/a&gt;.
As a wiki, many places are very well documented and you&amp;rsquo;re able to know exactly
were to stand or ask for drivers depending on were you want to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wanted to be in Bratislava in the evening, and I start walking to the
right hitchhicking spot around noon. I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew how many time it would take to
find a car heading to Bratislava, so I give myself plenty of time.&lt;br /&gt;
The spot was a petrol station. Once there, I saw a Slovakian car plate, I
waited for the owner to go out of the store and I simply asked if he was
going to Bratislava and if he could take me there. And he did. One hour latter
I was in Bratislava.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/successkid.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Way too easy&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Actually, it was the first time this driver took someone hitchhicking.&lt;br /&gt;
So, thumbs up, and don&amp;rsquo;t panic !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>