<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Czechia on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/czechia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Czechia on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 19:27:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/czechia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Prague</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/czechia/prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 19:27:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/czechia/prague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahoj !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Czechia has always been a country I wanted to discover, maybe because I met
some Czech people when I was younger and they impregnated me with their culture.&lt;br /&gt;
I know that spending some time in Prague, the capital, is not enough to really
feel a whole nation and all their history, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m only heading for big
cities by convenience, and will try to get off the beaten track latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prague is the kind of city I could live in. Big city, but plenty of space,
fresh air and a lot of green spot all over the town.&lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s actually a common topic of discussion with all the people I met so far,
everyone seems to agree that Paris is oppressive, much polluted, everybody
being put under stress.&lt;br /&gt;
Some huge cities are able to avoid this. Prague is.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/prague.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Taking some height&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When they build Prague, It&amp;rsquo;s like they didn&amp;rsquo;t care about the relief, they just
put the city from either side of the river, and the hills shaped the streets
and the buildings.&lt;br /&gt;
As a result, you&amp;rsquo;re always going up and down when walking, and
it opens the city and let you orientate yourself while enjoying the view.&lt;br /&gt;
Add on top of that a really good bus and tram network all over the town, and
beautiful buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, and the cost of life is ridiculously low. Eat a goulash AND have a
beer for less than 200 Czech crowns (around 7 euros). I stayed in a hostel for
5~7 euro the night, Food is cheap, means of transport are cheap, cigarettes are cheap,
at lest for us, French people. Obviously the Czech people have correlated incomes.&lt;br /&gt;
Nonetheless, they&amp;rsquo;ve got free education, free health care for all, and the
unemployment rate is at 5.3.&lt;br /&gt;
CQFD ?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/piano.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;An unexpected but pleasant encounter&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At night the city is more than alive. Bar, night club and underground places
all over the town if you know were to find them. And chances are that in most
bar you&amp;rsquo;ll find some jazz or blues bands. Even better, a piano free of use,
where people gathered with their own instrument, jamming together until
dawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that Budapest is even better for the same reasons, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see
in a few days !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>