<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vietnams on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vietnams on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hanoï</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/hanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/hanoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to check the stamps on my passport to realize that I spend two months in
Taiwan. Didn&amp;rsquo;t thought it was that long.&lt;br /&gt;
Even if I did so many differents and new things, I didn&amp;rsquo;t took the time to
write about it, or didn&amp;rsquo;t wanted to in fact.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve just arrived in Vietnam, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to start writting more !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan landed in Hanoi, the capital City. I missed the last bus to the down
town by a couple of minutes, so I was forced to use a cab, which cost me as
much as three nights in the hostel I&amp;rsquo;m staying in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hostel is anyway the cheapest I could find, it has pros and cons.
The beds are pretty much made of rocks, which is good for your back though.
As in a few places I&amp;rsquo;ve been so far in Asia, the shower is just a shower head
hanging on the wall of the bathroom. So it gets flooded in no time and even
brushing your teeth means having your feet wet.&lt;br /&gt;
I think I like this kind of places, when it just comes to your mind that some comfort
isn&amp;rsquo;t mandatory after all.&lt;br /&gt;
And for the pros, well for four Euros, you get a free breakfast, and free beer
at night if you get the timing right.&lt;br /&gt;
Which lead me to night life in the old town of Hanoi. A fellow backpacker told
me that a few years earlier the old town was were Vietnamese people would enjoy
foods and drinks, with what you can expect from the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; in old town.&lt;br /&gt;
Now it&amp;rsquo;s full of party hostel, occidental style bar and night clubs, and almost
all the costumers are either European or American.&lt;br /&gt;
As for the Vietnamese, they are only working here in hostel and bars, when they
aren&amp;rsquo;t asking if you want some beautiful girls for the night, drugs or scooter
rental.&lt;br /&gt;
So yeah, if you want to party with other backpackers, perfect place to be,
especially when there is no entrance fee, and the first drink is most of time
free, which mean you can spend the all night without spending any Dongs.
Everything is cheap anyway.&lt;br /&gt;
But there is almost no exchange and communication between Vietnamese and travelers, which I think we
should call Tourist - I mean, I do feel like a real tourist in Hanoi - Where in
Taiwan strangers would mixed nicely with local people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>