<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vietnams on Somewhere on Earth</title>
    <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vietnams on Somewhere on Earth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hanoï</title>
      <link>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/hanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/vietnam/hanoi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to check the stamps on my passport to realize that I spend almost two months in
Taiwan. Didn&amp;rsquo;t thought it was that long.&lt;br /&gt;
Don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to write about Taiwan, but if you have the chance to go
there, it&amp;rsquo;s kinda unique, you won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just arrived in Vietnam, so let me tell you a few thing about this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, here you are, landing in Hanoi, the capital City. If you see, like I
did, the only bus going to town at that time passing right in front of you when
you&amp;rsquo;ve just leaved the terminal, you&amp;rsquo;d be forced to use a cab, which will cost you as
much as three nights in the hostel you&amp;rsquo;re planning to stay in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hostel is anyway the cheapest you could find, with its pros and cons.
The beds are pretty much made of rocks, which is good for your back though.
As in a few places I&amp;rsquo;ve been so far in Asia, the shower is just a shower head
hanging on the wall of the bathroom. So it gets flooded in no time and even
brushing your teeth means getting your feet wet.&lt;br /&gt;
Keep it up ! It will remind you that some comfort isn&amp;rsquo;t mandatory after all.&lt;br /&gt;
And for the pros, well for four Euros, you get a free breakfast, and free beers
at night if you get the timing right.&lt;br /&gt;
Which lead me to night life in the old town of Hanoi. A fellow backpacker would
tell you that a few years earlier the old town was where Vietnamese people would enjoy
foods and drinks, with what you can expect from the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; in old town.&lt;br /&gt;
Now it&amp;rsquo;s full of party hostel, occidental style bar and night clubs, and almost
all the costumers are either European or American.&lt;br /&gt;
As for the Vietnamese, they are only working here in hostel and bars, when they
aren&amp;rsquo;t asking if you want some beautiful girls for the night, drugs or scooter
rental.&lt;br /&gt;
So yeah, if you want to party with other backpackers, perfect place to be,
especially when there is no entrance fee, and the first drink is most of time
free, which mean you can spend the all night without spending any Dongs.
Everything is cheap anyway.&lt;br /&gt;
But there is almost no exchange and communication between locals and travelers, which we
should call Tourist - I mean, I do feel like a real tourist in Hanoi - Where in
Taiwan strangers would mixed nicely with local people.&lt;br /&gt;
But wait, don&amp;rsquo;t feel like living the city too soon, for when it comes to food,
it gets better. You see these small plastic chairs on the pavement ? Come, have
a seat, and in no time someone will bring you tasty Vietnamese meal, enough to
fill your stomach for less than a dollar.&lt;br /&gt;
Now the street is finished in a outdoor restaurant, where you choose your meal
by choosing where to seat.&lt;br /&gt;
Enjoy your rice noodle, while listening to the horn symphony for motorbikes
and buses, and then we&amp;rsquo;ll be ready to leave the noisy city and explore the
country side.&lt;br /&gt;
There, will less effort, you might be able to know more about local culture and
way of live.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.somewhereonearth.xyz/images/article/intothewild.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Leaving the city, to more quiet places.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>